<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Techtalks on Enan's Blog</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/blog/techtalk/</link><description>Recent content in Techtalks on Enan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://3n4n.github.io/blog/techtalk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SSH Keys On a Shared Machine</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/blog/2022/11/ssh-keys-on-a-shared-machine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3n4n.github.io/blog/2022/11/ssh-keys-on-a-shared-machine/</guid><description>Services such as GitHub often requires an ssh connection. The user, say Bob, has to generate a key-pair to authenticate himself when communicating with the service. The generated key-pair exists in Bob’s machine in plaintext format.
The issue arises when Bob’s machine is shared among multiple users, some or all of whom has root access: they can access Bob’s key-pair, which will enable them to identify themselves as Bob and give them access to all services Bob has access to.</description></item><item><title>FFmpeg Tricks</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/blog/2022/07/ffmpeg-tricks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3n4n.github.io/blog/2022/07/ffmpeg-tricks/</guid><description>Clip a portion of a video The following command saves a five-second clip from input.mkv to output.mkv.
ffmpeg -i input.mkv -ss 00:05:10.500 -t 00:00:05.000 output.mkv -ss 00:05:10.500: start clipping at hh:mm:ss.ms -t 00:00:05.000: clip a duration of hh:mm:ss.ms Remove black borders The following steps consecutively detects and crops black borders around a video file. This tutorial assumes the aspect ratio of the video is the same across the whole video, i.</description></item><item><title>Using Claws Mail Client</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/blog/2020/08/using-claws-mail-client/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3n4n.github.io/blog/2020/08/using-claws-mail-client/</guid><description>Contents Why Install Add Account Compose Email FAQ Why? Why use an email-client? I do not know. Except that using an external email-client seems like a grown-up thing to do, like owning a wallet.
Why use Claws Mail? I guess because it uses less resource than others. But, having a modern computer, that sounds more like an excuse than a valid reason.
Basically, the reason will depend on the user.</description></item></channel></rss>