<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Filmtalks on Enan's Blog</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/filmtalk/</link><description>Recent content in Filmtalks on Enan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/filmtalk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fight Club: A Coming-of-Age Film</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/07/fight-club-a-coming-of-age-film/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/07/fight-club-a-coming-of-age-film/</guid><description>Disclaimer Like any ambiguous movie, Fight Club has many interpretations, and everyone is free to interpret it in their own way. That is the beauty of films, or any kind of art. The point of this essay is not to say your reading is wrong or that mine is right. The point is to write down my interpretation &amp;hellip; and that is all.
Introduction Due to its very nature, Fight Club has repeatedly been misunderstood by its fans and haters alike.</description></item><item><title>Midsommar and Emotional Dependency</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/07/midsommar-and-emotional-dependency/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/07/midsommar-and-emotional-dependency/</guid><description>Midsommar explores a variety of subjects: anxiety, insecurity, loss, grief, betrayal, abandonment issues. But the main theme of Midsommar is emotional dependency and the need to connect.
Dani and Christian: Case Study of a Couple Not in Love Dani is emotionally unstable. She is on prescription medicine for her anxiety and possibly has undiagnosed bipolar disorder. Her bipolar sister depends on her for support, but Dani doesn&amp;rsquo;t have anyone to talk to about her own problems.</description></item><item><title>Building a Character</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/04/building-a-character/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/04/building-a-character/</guid><description>Characters are the life force of a story. Yes, dazzling locations, thrilling plot, and heartwarming themes are all well and good, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t have well-developed characters, your story will fall flat on its misshapen ass. People don&amp;rsquo;t read stories for locations (they could browse Instagram for that), nor for plot (they could skim the synopsis if that was the case). People read stories for characters they could spend some alone time with without feeling lonely.</description></item><item><title>In Praise of Horror</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/04/in-praise-of-horror/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/04/in-praise-of-horror/</guid><description>Genre Snobbery Exists Ever heard of genre snobbery? It means laughing at a genre because some people decided it is beneath the taste of sophisticated people. Critiques and writers alike from literary fiction side have been turning up their noses at genre fiction since the beginning of time. These &amp;ldquo;unsophisticated&amp;rdquo; genres include Fantasy, Sci-Fi and Horror.
Sci-Fi and Fantasy are Awesome Thanks to celebrated writers like Ray Bradbury and H.G. Wells, Sci-Fi genre has garnered much deserved attention in literary societies.</description></item><item><title>Why Avatar: The Last Airbender Rocks</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/03/why-avatar-the-last-airbender-rocks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/03/why-avatar-the-last-airbender-rocks/</guid><description>Introduction This post is not about the James Cameron movie, neither is it about the Shyamalan adaptation. It is about the Nickolodeon show that has secured a place in the heart of every 2000&amp;rsquo;s kid like a cat curling up on its owner&amp;rsquo;s lap.
What is Avatar: The Last Airbender Avatar: The Last Airbender is a fantasy show featuring a trio of kids trying to save the world from a powerful and evil overlord.</description></item><item><title>Joker and Why We Love Him</title><link>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/01/joker-and-why-we-love-him/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://3n4n.github.io/enansblog/2020/01/joker-and-why-we-love-him/</guid><description>Introduction If there were a list of most popular characters in pop culture history, Batman and Joker would be near the top. The masked duo are the best example of Nemesis in creative media.
The Definitive Version For me and most of my generation, Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s The Dark Knight is the definitive version of Batman and Joker. There have been plenty of adaptations featuring these two characters, but none had the sweeping success and widespread recognition The Dark Knight had.</description></item></channel></rss>